# Julian Joseph

I am a senior software developer with over 20 years' commercial IT experience. I am self-motivated and enthusiastic with excellent communication and problem-solving skills and a very strong academic and technical background. I am a quick learner and always seeking to improve my existing knowledge and acquire new skills. I am dependable and hard-working, and a good team player with a pragmatic and positive approach.

#### **Availability**

I am currently taking a short break between contracts to pursue some personal training and technical projects. I am based in South West London and available immediately.

#### **Key Skills**

- Software design and development using C#/.NET Framework
- Relational Database Design, Development and Implementation with SQL Server
- BI/ETL Development using SSIS/SSRS
- Clean Code advocate
- Agile Software Development
- Test Driven Development
- Mentoring junior developers and providing clear and concise technical documentation for new team members

#### Qualifications

- UKSIP Level 3 Certificate in Investment Management
- Microsoft Certified Solution Developer (MCSD including SQL Server)
- Lloyd's of London Introductory Test
- MSc (Distinction) Information Systems Design University of Westminster
- BSc (Honours) Zoology University of Leeds

## **Recent Employment Experience**

### Nomura International - Senior Analyst/Developer (Contract) July 2015 - January 2018

Lead Developer on a global Product Control project, providing analysis and reporting on Front Office vs Middle Office reconciliation, price verification and testing and end of day position reporting. Working with a team based in London and Mumbai, the application was delivered using the following technologies and approaches:

- C# .NET using Visual Studio 2015
- SQL Server database
- Microservices using NancyFx and Web API
- Agile Methodology
- Test Driven Development
- Continuous Integration using Team City
- Source Code control with Subversion/TortoiseSVN

## My responsibilities included:

- Design and development of software components
- Mentoring and performing code reviews with junior off-shore developers
- Running daily scrum when required
- Assisting with recruitment interviews
- Authoring technical documentation
- Building a component to interface with an external SSAS Cube using custom MDX queries
- Building reusable C# ETL components to import CSV files into SQL Server database

#### UBS Global Asset Management - Senior BI Analyst/Developer (Contract) March 2015 - July 2015

Working in UBS Global Asset Management Risk Control IT Team. Developing, maintaining and supporting a Risk Reporting Data Warehouse system. Fund data and externally provided analytics data was consolidated using Markit EDM (ETL), then exported to an Oracle data warehouse. This drove a Business Objects Universe which allowed Risk Analysts to create and run their own reports.

#### Threadneedle Investments – Senior SQL Server/BI Developer (Contract) August 2012 – March 2015

#### **Main Projects**

<u>Project Robin</u>: Migration of Threadneedle's transfer agency to a new provider – including design, build and integration of new feeds into existing client holding data warehouse using SSIS; optimisation and tuning of existing SQL Server 2012 data warehouse to improve performance.

<u>Project Arrow</u>: Design and build a new data mart to support Front Office reporting requirements built in SSRS, and ensure seamless integration of re-structured data sources resulting from migration of Threadneedle's outsourced back office services to a new provider

#### Nomura International – Senior Analyst/Developer (Contract) November 2010 – August 2012

A Senior developer within the Finance Technology Product Control team. Worked on a strategic project to implement a new PnL reporting and reconciliation tool for global deployment in Nomura.

Main responsibilities included design and development of SSIS packages and stored procedures to perform ETL processes with PnL data; investigation and resolution of production issues; designing and deploying tools for use by Environment Management staff.

## Royal Bank of Scotland - Senior Analyst/Developer (Contract) April 2010 - October 2010

Member of Global Banking Prime Brokerage IT Team. Worked on streamlining new client onboarding process, and rationalisation of existing clients using SQL Server, SSIS and RBS in-house products.

#### Nomura International - Senior Analyst/Developer (Contract) Nov 2005 - March 2010

Member of Middle and Back Office Technology team. Worked on a wide range of intranet-based global applications within the Corporate, Finance and Operations functions of the bank, mainly implemented using ASP.NET and SQL Server. Key responsibilities included:

- Analysis/design of new projects
- Extending, modifying and enhancing existing applications
- Trouble-shooting and bug-fixing
- User support
- Mentoring users/developers from global offices

## ReformIS Solution Architects - Senior Consultant - Sep 2004 - Oct 2005

## Client Assignments:

## New Star Asset Management (Sep 2004 –Sep 2005)

Designed and developed a generic managed workflow system for input and collation of retail fund data from both internal sources and external data feeds. Fund data was mapped to a standard XML format, validated against a schema (XSD) and automatically published via an XML Web Service to a national centralised retail fund data hub. The workflow was managed using SQL Server DTS in conjunction with a C#.NET console application, with an ASP.NET/C# GUI.

## Rank Group Gaming Division (Jul 2004 - Sep 2004)

Developed and implemented an Operational Reporting system providing detailed analysis of bingo hall visit data held in the Rank data warehouse. The system was deployed nationally to all Mecca Club Managers. Designed and developed custom components using SSRS API to manage a suite of weekly reports, ASP.NET/C# web interface, and SQL Server 2000 objects required to extract and aggregate data efficiently from Rank data warehouse

## New Star Asset Management (Oct 2003 - Jul 2004)

Developed a SQL Server/SSIS-based system to administer an investment portfolio management service. Managed all technical aspects of the project, including authoring functional and technical specifications, systems architecture, design and implementation of database, website and web-based components, training and documentation for New Star users and support staff

## **Current Voluntary/Spare Time Projects**

- Volunteering at my local Code Club <a href="https://www.codeclub.org.uk">https://www.codeclub.org.uk</a>) helping children learn how to code using Scratch, Python & HTML
- Redesign and development of my cycling club's website (Dulwich Paragon <a href="http://www.dulwichparagon.com/">http://www.dulwichparagon.com/</a>)
- Learning Python and Python web development using Flask (using PluralSight courses)
- Learning MongoDB
- Various Raspberry Pi projects

#### **Hobbies and Interests**

- Cycling active member of Dulwich Paragon Cycling Club
- Music play guitar and piano, and regularly attend concerts
- Film/Literature
- Technology reading/listening to podcasts

#### Referees

• Available on request